Finding Aid for the Rudy Thomas Foley papers LSC.1708
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rudy Thomas Foley papers
1947-1984
UCLA Library Special Collections
Foley, Rudy Thomas
LSC.1708
6.0 linear feet
Rudy Thomas Foley (1947-1984) wrote plays, fiction, and poetry. The collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, manuscripts, audiotapes, reviews, programs, fliers and newsletters, clippings, and presentation copies of books.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9942330283606533
Biography
Foley was born on May 22, 1947; wrote plays, fiction, and poetry; he died on August 16, 1984 in California.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, manuscripts, audiotapes, reviews, programs, fliers and newsletters, clippings, and presentation copies of books.
Related Material
Dan Luckenbill papers (Collection 1484). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Authors, American -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Foley, Rudy Thomas, 1947-1984--Archives.
- Writings
  - General Information
    - Portfolio
      - Photographs, etc.
        - Includes stills from and clippings about the motion picture Greek Lightning, in which Rudy T. Foley had a role, resumes and photographs, promoting Rudy T. Foley as a model., 1970s (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Friend from Switzerland
        - Primarily postcards. Also photographs and souvenir books of Switzerland., Late 1960s. (Box 1)
    - Illness
      - Aids
        - Greeting cards received when ill, 1983-1984. (Box 1)
        - calendar. Marked with dates for chemo treatments, etc. Bernard Galm has noted August 5, Rudy died, and August 23, burial, Trappist, Kentucky., 1984 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, etc.
    - Howard Moss
      - Letters to Rudy T. Foley
        - August 24, 1979., 2 leaves. Typed, signed. (Box 2)
        - September 20, 1979., 1 leaf. Typed, signed. On (small)The New Yorker letterhead. (Box 2)
        - January 5, 1980., 1 leaf. Typed, signed. Also envelope. (Box 2)
        - February 5, 1980., 1 leaf. Typed, signed. On (larger)The New Yorker letterhead. (Box 2)
        - March 17, 1982., 1 (blue) card. Holograph, signed on verso. With 2 clippings and envelope. (Box 2)
        - March 23, 1982., 1 blue card. Typed, signed on verso. Also envelope. (Box 2)
        - November 18, 1982., 1 leaf. Typed, signed on verso. On (small)The New Yorker letterhead. (Box 2)
        - December 9, 1982., 1 leaf. Typed, signed on verso. On (small)The New Yorker letterhead. (Box 2)
        - n.d., 1 item. Small greeting card, signed. (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence
    - Various Family Members
      - Greeting cards and letters. (Box 2)
    - Bernard Galm
      - Correspondence With Rudy T. Foley
        - Greeting cards and letters, ca. 1976-1983. (Box 2)
    - Brother Paul, Abbey Of Gethsemani, Trappist, Kentucky
      - Correspondence With Rudy T. Foley
        - An extensive file with many enclosures., ca. 1972-1984. (Box 2)
  - Writings
    - Correspondence
      - Rudy T. Foley's letters and replies
        - Agents, publishers, editors, etc. Blueboy, In Touch, St Martin's Press, etc. primarily about his music criticism (Bravo) and his novel Thoroughbred. Includes several interesting responses including a critique by Kirby Congdon (2 leaves, photocopy), for example. (Box 2)
  - General Information
    - School Items
      - Los Angeles City College
        - Los Angeles City College Associate of Arts degree., January 1982. (Box 3)
  - Friendships, etc.
    - Copy of Manuscript by John Marvin
      - Interviews With Male Actors
        - Don Johnson, etc. (Box 3)
  - Writings
    - Plays
      - Foghorns
        - 2 copies. (Box 4)
      - The Marine Truckdriver
        - Two copies. (Box 4)
      - Summer Garden
        - Cassette recordings. 2 audiotapes (cassette). Rudy T. Foley produced this at the Evergreen Stage (5060 Fountain Avenue, Hollywood), Directed by Cecil Reddick., 1980. February-March 1980. (Box 4)
        - Various drafts, photographs, reviews, etc. 7 folders. Includes submission to a contest of gay plays. (Box 4)
        - Programs and fliers. One program signed by cast members. One version of fliers includes quotations from reviews Los Angeles Times, Free Press, and Drama - Logue. (Box 4)
    - Music Criticism
      - For KFAC magazine
        - These became the basis for a book, entitled Bravo., 1976-1977. (Box 5)
    - Plays
      - Various
        - Drafts, etc. (Box 5)
    - Fiction
      - Crocodiles
        - Rough draft and one later draft. Also filed (by Rudy T. Foley) in a later series with other writings. (Box 5)
      - Bahnhofstrasse [an excerpt from Thoroughbred]
        - In: Cygnet, vol.3 no.3 [a supplement to The Daily Bruin], April 19, 1978. (Box 6)
      - Thoroughbred
        - Various versions and copies. (Box 6)
  - Rudy T. Foley's Files
    - General
      - Appreciation of Music
        - KFAC articles and Bravo. (Box 7)
      - Book reviews, Critiques, History
        - Various drafts, etc. (Box 7)
      - Employment
        - UCLA. (Box 7)
      - Workman's Compensation Claim
        - UCLA. (Box 7)
  - Rudy T. Foley's Files [This File Kept By BG]
    - General
      - Memorial Items
        - Obituary, photograph of gravestone, copy of service at Gethsemani, etc. Other records included: birth ceritifcate, baptismal certificate.. Also letter from Dan Luckenbill to John Rechy. 2 leaves. typed, signed. Gives news of the death of Rudy T. Foley., November 7, 1984. (Box 7)
  - Rudy T. Foley's Files
    - General
      - Miscellaneous
        - unspecified (Box 7)
      - Novel
        - A version of Crocodiles, 1978. (Box 8)
      - Novel Revised
        - Versions of Thoroughbred (Box 8)
      - Novella
        - Torch Ridge, 1977. (Box 8)
      - Novel
        - Something Wicked, 2 copies., n.d. (Box 8)
      - Plays
        - Change for a Silver Dollar, Hell. (Box 8)
      - Poetry
        - Various. Includes letter about Adrienne Rich. Rudy T. Foley had been to a reading by Adrienne Rich and this letter describes that (to him) disappointing experience. (Box 9)
      - Play
        - The Cunt (Box 9)
      - Short Stories
        - Various titles. (Box 9)
      - Soviet Articles
        - School papers. (Box 9)
      - Track and Field
        - Mike Tully. Newspaper clippings, autographed program. (Box 9)
        - Letter from Mike Tully, 1 leaf. Holograph, signed. Rudy T. Foley had envisioned Mike Tully playing a role in a movie version of Thoroughbred, which Rudy T. Foley promoted., May 10, 1979. (Box 9)
      - Club 7 / 11
        - Newsletters, etc. Also draft for ad to be placed by Rudy T. Foley. (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous drafts, etc
        - Extensive folder. (Box 10)
  - Books Collected By Rudy T. Foley
    - Primarily Presentation and Gift Copies
      - Christopher Isherwood
        - Christopher and His Kind. For Thomas Foley in memory of Anais Nin, Christopher Isherwood, March 7, 1978. (Box 10)
        - My Guru and His Disciple. Happy Birthday from Christopher I., May 25, 1980. (Box 10)
      - Howard Moss
        - Instant Lives. For Rudy, with my fondest good wishes on Christmas Eve,, Howard. Los Angeles., 1982 (Box 10)
        - Finding Them Lost and Other Poems (paperback). For Rudy, on a sunny day, from Howard, December 1970. (Box 10)
      - John Rechy
        - The Fourth Angel, For Rudy and For Bernard: To Rudy, whose own beautiful books I'm looking forward to, friend. To Bernard: instant friend. Warmly, John. (Box 10)
        - Bodies and Souls (paperback). For Rudy: I hope your wonderful writing continues. Sincerely, J Rechy [no date]. (Box 10)
      - Tennessee Williams
        - Small Craft Warnings (paperback). Gift inscription from Dan Luckenbill: Rudi - Happy Birthday '78. Love, Dan. (Box 10)
  - General
    - Poster For Tricia's Wedding (The Cockettes) And Un Chant D'Amour
      - First time shown in New York.
        - Oversize Box., n.d. (Box 11)
    - Photograph [Nude] of Rudy T. Foley
      - Photographer Unknown
        - Damaged with cracking. (Box 11)
    - Other Photographs
      - Marina del Rey and the Victors' Garden
        - Small photographs and negatives. Rudy T. Foley lived in a garage apartment at the Victors' (Beverly Hills), where he did garden design and groundskeeping. (Box 11)
    - Calendar
      - The First Tom of Finland Calendar
        - Signed by Tom of Finland. Water damaged. Other reproductions of work by Tom are found throughout the papers (used as fliers, etc.)., 1978. (Box 11)